现在我们理解了流密码，那么我们继续下一话题
Now that we understand stream ciphers,
we're gonna move on and talk about a more
【伊卡酱 译注】
我们来看看更为强大的原型：分组密码
一个分组密码由两部分构成
powerful primitive called a block cipher.
So a block cipher is made up of two
E和D，分别是加密和解密算法
algorithms, E and D. These are encryption
and decryption algorithms. And both of
这两个算法都以一个密钥K为输入
现在，分组密码的特点是
these algorithms take, as input, a key K.
Now, the point of a block cipher is that
它取N位明文作为输入
它的输出与输入具有严格相同的位数
it takes an N bit plain text as input, and
it outputs exactly the same number of bits
所以他将输入的N位字符串
映射到输出的N位字符串
as outputs. So it maps N bits on inputs to
exactly N bits of outputs. Now there are
有两个分组密码的经典例子
第一个叫做3DES
two canonical examples of block ciphers.
The first one is called triple-DES. In
在3DES中，分组大小，即输入位数，为64
triple-DES the block size, namely the
number of input bits, is 64. So triple-DES
所以3DES将64位分组映射到64位分组
它使用一个128位长的密钥
will map 64-bit blocks to 64-bit blocks
and it does it using a key that's 168 bits long.
我们在下一节讨论3DES的构建
We're gonna talk about how Triple DES
is built in the next segment.
另一个更新的分组密码叫AES
Another block cipher, which is more
recent, is called AES. Now, AES has
AES的参数略有不同，它的分组大小为128位
slightly different parameters. So, here
the block size is 128 bits.
所以AES将128位分组映射到128位分组
So, AES will map a 128 bits of input
to 128 bits of output.
实际上AES有三种可能的密钥大小
我把这些密钥大小写在这里
And it actually has three possible sizes
of keys, and I wrote down these sizes over here.
密钥越长，密码工作的速度越慢
Basically the longer the key, the slower the cipher is,
但是大概越安全
but presumably the
more secure it is to break and we're gonna
我们稍后讨论分组密码安全性的意义
talk about what it means for block ciphers
to be secure in just a minute. Now block
典型的分组密码以迭代的形式构建。
它们输入密钥K，例如
ciphers are typically built by iteration. They
take in as input a key K, for example
在AES中，密钥可以是128位长。首先
in the case of AES the key could be 128
bits long, and the first thing that
将密钥扩张成一系列的回合密钥K1到Kn
happens to the key is that it gets expanded
into a sequence of keys K1 to Kn called
现在，使用这些回合密钥的方法
round keys. Now, the way the cipher
uses these round keys is by iteratively
是一次又一次地迭代加密明文信息
并使用一个叫回合函数的
encrypting the message again and again and
again using what's called a round
这里我们有这个两输入的函数R
function. So here we have this function R
that take two inputs. This function R is
这个函数R叫做回合函数
它的一个输入是回合密钥
gonna be called a round function. It takes
as input the round key, and it takes as
另一个输入是当前的信息状态
这里我们有输入的明文信息
input the current state of the message.
So here we have our input message. Say,
对于AES，明文信息是严格的128位，
这是因为AES的明文分组为严格的128位。
for AES, the message would be 128 bits
exactly, because each block in AES is
首先我们应用第一个回合函数
exactly 128 bits. And then the first thing
that happens is we apply the first round
使用回合密钥K1来对信息操作
然后我们得到了一些新信息
function using the key K1 to the
message. And we get some new message out,
然后我们取这个新信息m1，应用下一个回合函数
as a result. Then we take this message m1,
we apply the next round function to
使用一个不同的密钥k2。然后我们得到了下一轮的信息
it using a different key, using the key k2.
Then we get the next round message out.
一直下去，直到所有的回合都完事了
And so on and so forth until all the
rounds have been applied and then the
最后的输出实际上就是加密结果。AES也是这种情况
final output is actually the result of the
cipher. And again this would be also
AES是128位的。加密结果也是128位的
in the case of AES, this was 128 bits. And
the resulting cipher text would also be
现在，不同的密码有不同的回合数
128 bits. Now, different ciphers have
different number of rounds, and they have
有不同的回合函数。例如
3DES的回合数是48
different round functions. So, for
example, for triple DES the number
我们会看到3DES的回合函数是怎样工作的
of rounds is 48. And we're gonna see
exactly how the round function for triple
例如AES的回合数只有10
DES works. For AES, for
example, the number of rounds
稍后我们也会看到AES的回合函数
is only ten, and again, we're gonna look
at how the round functions for AES
是怎样工作的
work as well in just a minute.
在这之前，我想提一下相关性能参数
Before we do that, I just wanted to
mention performance numbers.
大家看，这些是相关性能参数
So you can see here, these are
the performance numbers
两个典型分组密码，3DES和AES的参数
for the two typical block ciphers,
triple DES and AES.
这些是流密码的相关性能参数
And these are the corresponding
numbers for the stream ciphers
流密码我们上一章看过了
that we looked at in the previous module.
可以看出分组密码
And if you see that the block ciphers are
比流密码慢得多，但我们将看到
considerably slower than stream ciphers.
But we'll see that we can
分组密码能做的很多事情
使用类似RC4的流密码的话
do many things with block ciphers that we
couldn't do very efficiently with,
不能很有效地完成。现在我这周的目标是
告诉大家分组密码是如何工作的
constructions like RC4. Now my goal for
this week is to show you how block ciphers work,
更重要的，我想告诉大家
如何正确地使用分组密码
but more importantly I want to show
you how to use block ciphers correctly,
对于加密或完整性，或者
不管什么你能想到的应用
for either encryption or integrity or
whatever application you have in mind.
为了告诉大家怎么正确使用分组密码
So to show you how to use block ciphers
correctly, it actually makes a lot of sense
适当地抽象一点概念会更有道理
这样我们可以有一个分组密码的
to abstract the concept a little bit so we have a clean,
abstract concept of a block cipher
清晰的定义。然后我们可以证明和推断
哪些加密机制是正确的
to work with. And then we can argue and reason
about what constructions are correct and
哪些是错误的。一个分组密码的非常优雅的抽象概念
what constructions are incorrect. And so
an abstraction, it's a very elegant abstraction of a
叫做伪随机函数
block cipher is what's called a
pseudorandom function, a pseudorandom
伪随机置换。让我解释一下这些概念：
一个伪随机函数
permutation. So let me explain what these
things are. So a pseudorandom function
定义在密钥空间，输入空间和输出空间上
basically is defined over a key space, an
input space, and an output space.
伪随机函数取一个密钥、输入,
And all it is, is basically a function that takes
a key and an input as inputs and outputs
输出输出空间中某个元素。好，
它从K和X中各取一个元素
some element in the output space. Okay, so
it takes an element in K, an element in X,
输出Y中的一个元素。然后唯一的要求是
and outputs an element in Y. And the only
requirement essentially, is that there's
有一个有效的方法来计算这个函数。
对于我们不需要是可逆的函数
an efficient way to evaluate the function.
For functions we're not requiring that
我们只需要它们是可计算的，给定密钥和输入x
they be invertible, we just need them to
be evaluatable, given the key and the input x.
现在，有一个有关概念可以更准确地抓住分组密码的特征
Now, a related concept that more
accurately captures what a block cipher is
叫做伪随机置换
it's called a pseudo-random
permutation. So a pseudo-random
伪随机置换也是定义在密钥空间和一个集合X上
permutation is, again, defined over a key
space, and then just a set X. And what it
它取密钥空间中的一个元素和X中一个元素
does is it takes an element in the key
space, an element of X, and outputs,
输出X中的一个元素。现在
通常函数E是容易计算的
basically, one element in X. Now, as
usual, the function E should be easy to
所以应当有一个算法来计算函数E
evaluate. So there should be an algorithm
to evaluate the function E. But more
但更重要的，一旦固定密钥K，
函数E是一一对应的，这点是重要的
importantly, once we fix the key K, it's
important that this function E be one-to-one.
换句话说，如果你考虑这里的集合X
In other words, if you think of the
space X as the set here, and here's the
函数也映射到X，然后函数E是双射的
same set X again, then basically the
function E, what it does, is, it's a one-to-one
所以X中的每一个元素被严格映射到X中的一个元素
function, so every element in X
gets mapped to exactly one element in X.
然后因为它是一一映射的，它当然是可逆的
And then because it's one to one, of
course it's also invertible. So given some
所以给定一些输出，当然有一个输入
可以被映射到那个输出
output there's only one input that maps to
that output. And the requirement is that
要求有一个有效的逆向算法
叫做D，输入特定输出
there is an efficient inversion algorithm,
call it D, that given a particular output,
会输出特定输出的原像
will output the original preimage that
mapped to that output. So really, a
一个伪随机置换非常精确地
抓住了分组密码的特点
pseudorandom permutation captures very
accurately and syntactically what a block
通常我不区分这些术语：
分组密码，或是伪随机置换
cipher is, and often I'll use the terms
interchangeably, either a block cipher or
我会根据上下文选择术语
a pseudorandom permutation. I'll use
whichever term depending on the context
好的，我们有两个例子，前面说过
where we're discussing things. Okay,
so we have two examples, as we said, of
关于伪随机置换的，3DES和AES
比如说AES128
pseudorandom permutations, triple DES and
AES, say for AES-128. The key space would
密钥空间是128位，输出也是128位。
我们说过，对于3DES
be 128 bits and the output space would be
128 bits. For Triple DES, as we said, the
分组大小仅为64位。密钥空间168位
block size is only 64 bits. And the key
size is 168 bits, okay. So we'll use
这些例子贯穿本课程，只要我一说PRP
these running examples actually
throughout, so whenever I say a PRP, concretely
(PRP:伪随机置换)
你就应当具体地想到AES或3DES
you should be thinking AES or
triple DES. Now one thing that I
我想指出，事实上任何伪随机置换
wanted to point out is that in fact any
pseudo-random permutation, namely any block
即任何分组密码，你可想到一个PRF。
事实上PRP是个具有更多结构的PRF
cipher, you can also think of it as a PRF.
In fact a PRP is a PRF that has more structure.
(PRF:伪随机函数)
特别地，一个PRP是一个输入空间等于输出空间的PRF
In particular, a PRP is a PRF where
the input space and the output space are
即X等于Y，事实上可以有效地求逆
the same, so X is equal to Y, and in
fact is efficiently invertible once you
一旦你有密钥k，好的，某种意义上
PRP是PRF的特例
have the secret key k. Okay. So
in some sense a PRP is a special case of a
尽管这并不准确，我们待会解释
PRF, although that's not entirely accurate,
and we'll see why in just a second.
目前，我们描述了伪随机置换
So, so far, we just described the,
kind of, the syntactic definition of what
和伪随机函数的字面定义。现在
is a pseudo random permutation and a
pseudo random function. So now, let's talk
我们来讨论PRF或PRP安全的意义
about what it means for a PRF or a PRP to
be secure. And this concept will
这个概念抓住了分组密码安全的本质
essentially capture what it means for a
block cipher to be secure, okay? So this
这是为什么我想在看具体加密机制前
is why I wanted to show you these
definitions, before we look at actual
为大家展示这些定义，这样一来
大家就很清楚我们要构建什么样的密码
block cipher constructions, so at least
it's clear in your mind what it is we're
好，那么这里我有个PRF，这里我需要一点记号
trying to construct. Okay, so here we have
a PRF. And I'm gonna need a little bit of
不太多，我需要定义集合“X,Y的函数”
notation, not too much though, so I'm gonna
need to define the set "Funs of X, Y".
这是所有从集合X映射到集合Y的函数的集合
This is basically the set of all functions from
the set X to the set Y, denoted here as a
用一个大圈来表示之。现在这个集合
非常之大，它的大小
big circle, Funs[X, Y]. Now this set is
gigantic. Its size is basically, you know,
是Y的大小的|X|次方，以AES为例
the size of Y to the size of X, so for
example for AES, remember both X and Y
记得X和Y都是2的128次方，故对于AES，
这个函数集合的大小非常庞大
would be 2 to the 128, so for AES the
size of the set is enormous. It'll be
大小是2的128次方的2的128次方次方，
是双重指数
2 to the 128 times 2 to the 128.
So it's kind of a double exponential.
非常大的数，比宇宙中的粒子数都多
So this is a gigantic number, this is more
particles than there are in the universe.
先不管这个，我们可以抽象地考虑这个集合
But regardless, we can kind of think of
this set abstractly. We never have to kind of
我们不必要写下来，我们可以脑补之，
不必担心如何计算它
write it down, we can just keep it in
our head and not worry about computing on it.
这是个非常大的集合，所有从X到Y的函数的集合
So this is a particular gigantic set
of the set of all functions from X to Y.
现在我们看一个小很多的函数集合
Now we're gonna look at a much smaller
set of functions, namely I'll call this set
我把它叫做S_F，表示从X到Y的全体函数
S sub F, and that's gonna denote the
set of all functions from X to Y that are
由PRF指定的，而且固定密钥k
specified by the PRF as soon as we
fix the particular key k. Okay so,
好的，我们固定密钥k，让第二个参数浮动
we fixed the key k, we let the second
argument float, and that basically defines
这就定义了一个从X到Y的函数。然后
我们看对所有密钥空间中可能的密钥，
a function from X to Y. Then we're going
to look at the set of all such functions
对所有这样的函数组成的集合。
好，如果大家再想想
for all possible keys in the key space.
Okay, so, if you think about it again,
对于AES，我们用128位密钥，这个的大小，
我们说S_AES，是2的128次方
for AES, if we're using 128-bit keys, the size of
this, I'll say S-AES, is basically going to be
比X到Y全体函数的个数少得多
2 to the 128, so much, much, much
smaller than the set of all possible
现在，我们说，一个PRF是安全的
functions from X to Y. And now, we say
that a PRF is secure, basically if a
如果一个随机函数从X映射到Y，
这里随机的意思是任取一个函数
random function in, from X to Y. So we
literally, we pick some arbitrary function
从X到Y全体函数这个大集合里面任取。
我们说这个PRF是安全的
in this gigantic set of all functions from
X to Y. And we say that the PRF is secure,
如果事实上一个从X到Y的随机函数，
与从X到Y的伪随机函数
if, in fact, a random function from X to Y
is indistinguishable from a pseudo-random
不可区分。当我们从集合S_F里
选取一个随机函数时
function from X to Y. Namely, when we pick
a random function from the set SF.
好，说得再清楚点
Okay. So, more precisely basically again,
在伪随机函数集合上的均匀分布
the uniform distribution on the set
of pseudorandom functions
与全体函数上的均匀分布不可区分
is indistinguishable from the
uniform distribution on the set of all functions.
让我讲得再精确点
Let me be just a little bit more precise,
给大家更直观的表达我这里的意思
just to give you a little bit more
intuition about what I mean by that and then we'll
然后我们再去看实际的加密机制。
我更准确地说明PRF安全的意义
move on to actual constructions. So let me
a bit more precise about what it means for
那么我们做如下事情
a PRF to be secure. And so what we'll do
is basically the following. So we have our
我们有攻击者，他试图区分真随机函数和伪随机函数
adversary, who's trying to distinguish
truly random function from a pseudo-random
我们让它们互相互动
function. So what we'll do is let them
interact with one of the two. So here in
在这个顶端的云，我们选择一个真随机函数。
在底端的云
the top cloud, we're choosing a truly
random function. In the bottom cloud,
我们选择一个随机密钥，计算伪随机函数
we're just choosing a random key for a
pseudo-random function. And now what this
现在这个攻击者上传一些X中的点
adversary's gonna do is he's gonna submit
points in X. So he's gonna submit a bunch
他将上传一些X。事实上，他将反复做这件事情
of Xs. In fact, he's gonna do this again
and again and again. So he's gonna
他会提交X1, X2. X3, X4,然后对每一个询问
submit X1, X2. X3, X4, and then for each
one of, of those queries, we're gonna give him
我们给他真随机函数在点X处的值
either the value of the truly random
function at the point X, or the value of
或是伪随机函数在点X处的值
好，攻击者不知道他得到的
the pseudorandom function at the point X.
Okay, so the adversary doesn't know which
是哪一种。顺便一提，对所有询问
他总是得到随机函数值
ones he's getting. By the way, for all
queries, he's always getting either the truly
或者是伪随机函数。换句话说
random function, or the pseudorandom
function. In other words, he's either
攻击者的所有询问和一个真随机函数互动
interacting with a truly random function
for all his queries, or he's interacting
或者和一个伪随机函数互动
with a pseudorandom function for all his
queries. And we say that the PRF is
我们说PRF是安全的，如果可怜的攻击者
无法区别其中的不同
secure if this poor adversary can't tell the
difference. He cannot tell whether he's
攻击者无法区分他是和一个真随机函数互动
还是和一个伪随机函数互动
interacting with a truly random function
or interacting with a pseudo random
好，我们稍后还会回来
并更精确地定义PRF
function. Okay, and we're gonna come back
actually later on and define PRFs more
现在，我想给大家介绍安全PRF的直观思想
precisely but for now, I wanted to give
you the intuition for what it means for PRFs to be secure
这样大家就能理解我们在构建什么
so you'll understand what it is that we're
trying to construct when we construct
当我们构建伪随机函数时。我想说
these pseudorandom functions. And I
should say that the definition for a
伪随机置换的定义其实差不多一样
pseudorandom permutation is pretty much
the same, except instead of choosing a
除了不是选择随机函数，我们在集合X上
选择一个随机置换
random function, we're going to choose a
random permutation on the set X. In other
换句话说，集合X上一个随机一一映射的函数。
攻击者可以询问
words, a random one-to-one function on the
set X. The adversary can either query this
这个X上的随机函数，或者询问
一个伪随机函数
random function on the set X, or he can
query a pseudorandom permutation, and the
PRP是安全的，如果攻击者不能区分
PRP is secure if the adversary cannot
tell the difference. Okay, so again the
好，目标是让这些函数和置换
goal is to make these functions and
permutations look like truly random
看起来像真的随机函数和置换，好
我们看一个简单问题
functions or permutations. Okay. So let's
look at a simple question. So suppose we
假设我们有一个安全PRF，记为F
它定义在集合X上
have a secure PRF. So we know this PRF
F. Happens to be defined in the set X. And
它一次输出128位
it so happens, you know, it outputs 128
bits every time. It so happens that this
这个PRF不能从X到｛0，1｝^128的
随机函数中被区分出来
PRF cannot be distinguished from a truly
random function from X to ｛0,1｝ to the 128.
现在我们要构建一个新PRF，记为G
Now we're gonna build a new PRF. Let's
call this PRF G. And the PRF G is gonna be
G如下定义，若x等于0，G总是输出0
defined as follows. We say, if x is equal
to zero, always output zero. Otherwise,
否则，若x不等于0，G输出F的值
那么我的问题是
if x is not equal to zero, just output the
value of F. So, my question to you is,
G是安全的PRF吗？
do you think this G is a secure PRF?
答案当然不是
Well, so, the answer, of course, is that its very easy
我们很容易区分函数G和真随机函数
to distinguish the function G from a random
function. All the adversary has to do
攻击者只需要询问X=0的函数值
对于一个真的随机函数
is just query the function at X=0.
For a random function, the probability
这一点上函数值等于0的概率是
1除以2的128次方
that the result is gonna be zero is one
over 2 to the 128. Whereas for the
而对于这个伪随机函数，他总是得到0
因为在0这个点处
pseudo-random function, he's always gonna
get zero. Because at zero, the function is
函数总是定义为0，无论什么密钥
always defined to be zero, no matter what
the key. And so all he would do is he
他会说，我在和一个伪随机函数互动
如果他在X=0处得到0
would say, hey, I'm interacting with a
pseudo-random function if he gets zero at X=0,
他会说，我在和一个真随机函数互动
如果他在X=0处得到的不是0
and he'll say I'm interacting with
a random function if he gets nonzero at X=0.
所有很容易区分G和真随机函数
So it's very easy to distinguish
this G from random. So what this example shows
这个例子说明了即使你有一安全PRF
对于一个已知的输入
is that even if you have a secure PRF,
it's enough that on just one known input
若输出不随机，被固定了，
那么这个PRF就被破解了
the output is kinda not random, the
output is fixed, and already the PRF is broken,
即使你知道这个PRF的其他地方
even though you realize that
everywhere else the PRF is perfectly
和真随机一点都无法区分
好，我来告诉大家PRF的威力
indistinguishable from random. Okay, so
let's just show you the power of PRFs.
我们看一个很简单的应用
我想告诉大家事实上
Let's look at a very easy application. I want to
show you that in fact pseudorandom functions
伪随机函数可以直接给我们一个
伪随机数发生器
directly give us a pseudorandom generator.
Okay. So, let's assume we have
那么，假设有一伪随机函数
从N位字符串映射到N位字符串
a pseudo random function. So this one
happens to go from N bits to N bits. And then,
然后我们定义如下发生器
种子空间取这个PRF的密钥空间
let's define the following generator.
Its seed space is going to be the
发生器的输出空间为t个
key space for the PRF, and its output
space is gonna be, basically, t blocks of
N位的分组。好，大家可以看到，输出一共有nt位
n bits each. Okay, so you can see the
output is a total of n times t bits for
我们可以选择某个参数t
some parameter T that we can choose. And
it turns out, basically, you can do this
实际上你可以做这个简单的构造
这有时叫做计数器模式
very simple construction, this is
sometimes called counter mode,
取PRF，计算其在0的值
where essentially, you take the PRF and you
evaluate it at zero, you evaluate it at one,
计算其在1的值，计算其在2的值，3的值，
4的值，直到t，然后将这些值联结起来
you evaluate it at two, at three, at
four, up to T, and you concatenate all these values.
这是个发生器，对吧？
我们取PRF的密钥
That's the generator, okay?
So we basically took the key for the PRF
把它扩张成nt位字符串
好的，这个生成器的一个重要性质是
and we expanded it into n times t bits.
Okay. A key property of this generator is
它是可并行计算的。我的意思是
如果你有两个处理器或两核
that it's parallelizable. What I mean by that
is if you have two processors or two cores
可供计算，那么你就可以让一核
计算所有偶数位置的输出
that you can compute on, then you can have
one core compute the even entries of the
另一核计算所有奇数位置的输出
output, and you can have another core
compute the odd entries of the output.
所有如果你有两核，你运行这个发生器
So basically, if you have two cores, you can
make this generator run twice as fast as
会比单核的快出一倍。这个性质好
it would if you only have a single core.
So the nice thing about this is, of
当然，我们知道伪随机数发生器
给我们带来流密码
course, we know that pseudo-random
generators give us stream ciphers, and so
所以这是一个可并行的流密码的例子。我想指出
this is an example of a parallelizable stream
cipher. And I just wanted to point out
我们看过的很多流密码，比如RC4
that many of the stream ciphers that we
looked at before, for example, RC4,
它们是先天串行的，即使你有两个处理器
those were inherently sequential. So even if you
had two processors, you couldn't make the
你也无法让这个流密码工作地比单处理器快
stream cipher work any faster than if you
just had a single processor. Now the main
现在主要问题是，为什么这个发生器安全？
这里我给大家一点直观的解释
question is why is this generator secure?
And so here I'm only gonna give you a
今后我们会更准确地补完之
little bit of intuition and we're gonna
come back and argue this more precisely
这个安全性直接由PRF的安全性而来
later on. But I'll just say that security
basically falls directly from the PRF property.
我们推导其安全性的方法，
是根据PRF安全性的定义
And the way we reason about security,
is we say, well this PRF by definition
与128位真随机函数不可区分
is indistinguishable from a truly
random function on 128 bits.
换句话说，如果我取这个发生器，
而不是用一个真随机函数
So in other words, if I take this generator and
instead I define a generator using a truly
定义的发生器，我把两者的输出结果写成
random function, in other words, I'll
write the output of the generator as
f(0)和f(1)，等等，使用真随机函数
f(0) concatenated f(1), and so on
and so forth, using a truly random function,
使用真随机函数的发生器的输出
then the output of the
generator using the truly random function
和使用伪随机函数的发生器的输出
would be indistinguishable from
the output of the generator using
不可区分。这是PRF安全性的本质
a pseudorandom function. That is the essence of
the security property of a PRF. But with
使用真随机函数，大家注意到
输出结果是真随机的
a truly random function, you notice that
the output is just truly random. Because
因为对于一个真随机函数，f(0)是随机值
f(1)是一个独立的随机值
for a truly random function, f(0) is
a random value. f(1) is an independent
f(2)是一个独立的随机值，等等
random value. f(2) is an independent
random value, and so on and so forth.
所以整个输出是一个随机的输出
所以用真随机函数
So the entire output is a truly random
output. And so with a truly random function,
发生器可以生成真随机输出，
所以是完美的安全
a generator produces truly random outputs,
and is therefore a perfectly secure
这样大家就看出为什么PRF有安全性
generator. And so you see how the PRF
security property lets us argue security.
我们说，当我们用真随机函数
替换掉伪随机函数PRF时
Basically, we argue that when we replace
the PRF with a truly random function, the
加密机制必须是安全的
construction is necessarily secure, and
that says that the construction with a
这也意味着用伪随机函数的加密也是安全的
对吧？我们稍后看几个例子
pseudorandom function is also secure.
Okay? And we're gonna see a couple more
现在大家理解分组密码是什么了
examples like this later on. So now you
understand what a block cipher is, and you
也直观地理解了
我们要获得什么样的安全性
have intuition for what security
properties it's trying to achieve.
下一节里我们看具体的分组密码机制
And in the next segment, we're gonna look at
constructions for block ciphers.